Finding Aid for Alexander Jefferson papers, 1921-2006
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated
  - Press
    - 1942 Life Magazine (Box 4)
    - 1942-1945 Walterboro Air Force Base in the Press And Standard (Box 4)
    - 1943 Time Magazine (Box 4)
    - 1945 (Box 4)
    - 1972-1979 (Box 4)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 4)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 4)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 4)
    - 1995-1998 (Box 4)
    - 1999-2000 (Box 4)
    - 2001-2002 (Box 4)
    - 2003-2004 (Box 5)
    - 2005-2006 (Box 5)
    - Undated (Box 5)
  - Public Appearances
    - 1983 (Box 5)
    - 1993-2000 (Box 5)
    - 1998 Speaker's Bureau Seminar (Box 5)
    - 2003-2006 (Box 5)
    - Undated, Speech Guide (Box 5)
- Tuskegee Airmen Detroit Chapter
  The Tuskegee Airmen Detroit Chapter series (0.8 linear feet) is divided into five sub-series: Correspondence; History; Organization containing meeting minutes from 1972-2005 (excepting 1983-1988); Press, and Public Appearances, which details the organization's involvement in sponsoring a career week event during African American History Week/Month.
  - Correspondence
    - 1974 (Box 5)
    - 2003 (Box 5)
  - History
    - Brief History (Box 5)
    - "Detroit Chapter, Tuskegee Airmen," 1998 (Box 5)
    - Flyer (Box 5)
    - Statement Regarding Desegregation in Detroit Public Schools 1976 (Box 5)
  - Organization
    - Book Sale 1999 (Box 5)
    - Browne, Ernest C., Commander, Selection of 1974 (Box 5)
    - Buford, Guion, Astronaut, Reception 1983 (Box 5)
    - Committees and Officers 1975-1981 (Box 5)
    - Constitution, By-laws, and Preamble (Box 5)
    - Dinner 1975 (Box 5)
    - Dues 1976 (Box 5)
    - Meeting Minutes
      - 1972-1973 (Box 5)
      - 1975-1977 (Box 5)
      - 1978-1982 (Box 5)
      - 1986-1996 (Box 5)
      - 1997-1999 (Box 5)
      - 2001-2005 (Box 5)
    - Membership Applications circa 1975 (Box 5)
    - Membership Directories
      - 1972 (Box 5)
      - 1973 (Box 5)
      - 1974 (Box 5)
      - 1975 (Box 5)
      - 1976 (Box 5)
      - 1978 (Box 5)
      - 1979 (Box 5)
      - 1981 (Box 5)
      - 1982 (Box 5)
      - 1984 (Box 5)
      - Undated (Box 5)
    - Membership Invitation and Application circa 1980 (Box 5)
    - Newsletters
      - 1972-1997 (Box 5)
      - 1998-2006 (Box 5)
    - Resolution in the Event of Death (Box 5)
    - Resolution to Honor Maj. William Whitfield Stephenson (Box 5)
    - Scholarship Applications 1984 (Box 5)
    - Speaker's Bureau Rosters 2001-2006 (Box 5)
    - Telephone Alert Network (Box 5)
    - Tuskegee Airmen Academy, Proposal for the Establishment of 1994 (Box 5)
  - Public Appearances
    - African American Aviation History and Career Awareness Week 2000-2006 (Box 5)
    - African American History Week 1976-1985 (Box 5)
    - African American History Month Career Week 1992-1996 (Box 5)
    - Speech Transcripts
      - 1979 (Box 5)
      - Undated, Detroit School Board (Box 5)
    - 2002-2003 (Box 5)
    - Undated, Sterling Heights International Festival (Box 5)
- Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum
  The Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum series (0.5 linear feet) contains three sub-series: Correspondence; Organization records which include invitations from the annual Salute and Reception Dinner; and Press.
  - Correspondence
    - 1995, 1998, 2002 (Box 6)
    - 2004 (Box 6)
      (including copies of letters dated 1941, 1942)
  - Organization
    - Advisory Board circa 1998 (Box 6)
    - Articles of Incorporation 1986 (Box 6)
    - Audit of Financial Statements 1983, 1996, 2000 (Box 6)
    - Black Wings Exhibit Loan, 1985, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Black Wings Exhibit Opening, 1984 (Box 6)
    - Board of Governors, Elected Members 1991-2005 (Box 6)
    - Brochures (Box 6)
    - By-laws 1993 (Box 6)
    - Casino Night Fundraiser 1983 (Box 6)
    - Docent Schedule 1997, 2000-2001 (Box 6)
    - Exhibit Concepts (Box 6)
    - Expansion Proposal 1997-1999 (Box 6)
    - Feasibility Study 1994 (Box 6)
    - Five Year Budget 1996 (Box 6)
    - Inventory 1996 (Box 6)
    - Inventory and Preservation Committee 1984 (Box 6)
    - Inventory, Audio Visual 1983 (Box 6)
    - Kick-Off Soiree 1981 (Box 6)
    - Lease, Draft 2002 (Box 6)
    - Management Consultant For The Arts Report 1996 (Box 6)
    - Meeting Minutes
      - 1989-1995 (Box 6)
      - 1996-2004 (Box 6)
    - Purchase of A75N1 Trainer 1991 (Box 6)
    - Purchase of Aircraft 1997 (Box 6)
    - Salute And Reception Dinner
      - 1987, 1989, 1993 Invitations (Box 6)
      - 1996 (Box 6)
      - 1997 (Box 6)
      - 1998 (Box 6)
      - 1999 (Box 6)
      - 2000 (Box 6)
      - 2002 (Box 6)
      - 2003 (Box 6)
      - 2004 (Box 6)
      - List of Speakers 1986-2000 (Box 6)
    - Tenth Anniversary Celebration 1996 (Box 6)
    - Traveling Exhibit Information (Box 6)
    - Tutorial Program 1990 (Box 6)
  - Press
    - 1984-1989 (Box 6)
    - 1998-2003 (Box 6)
- Photographs
  The Photograph series (0.5 linear feet) is divided in the same manner as the rest of the collection with sub-series for Alexander Jefferson, Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated, Tuskegee Airmen Detroit Chapter, and Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum. Many of the photographs are printouts from various Internet sites or photographs of photographs. The hand-written notes may prove useful for future researchers seeking to identify individuals in already-published but unlabeled photos from the World War II era.
  - Alexander Jefferson
    - Childhood (Box 6)
    - World War II Era (Box 6)
    - 1952 (Box 6)
    - 1966-1970 undated, Pattengill School (Box 6)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 6)
    - 1979 (Box 6)
    - 1995 (Box 6)
    - 2001 (Box 6)
    - 2003 (Box 6)
    - 2005 (Box 6)
    - 2006 (Box 6)
    - Undated, with General Colin Powell (Box 6)
    - Undated (Box 6)
    - Undated (Folder 1)
  - Tuskegee Airmen Incorporated
    - World War II Era (Box 6)
    - World War II Era (Library of Virginia Internet site) (Box 6)
    - 1949 Last Hurrah (Box 6)
    - 1955 "Dodo" Reunion (Box 6)
    - 1985 Photo Calendar (Box 6)
    - 1988 Lee "Buddy" Archer and Wendell O. Pruitt Illus. (Folder 1)
      (located in UAm)
    - 1995 (Box 6)
    - 1999, 2000 Handleman Sky Ranch (Box 6)
    - 2001 (Box 6)
    - 2002 National Convention (Box 6)
    - July 2003 Dayton, Ohio (Box 6)
    - 2004 Grand Forks Air Force Base, North Dakota (Box 6)
    - circa 2005 (Box 6)
    - Undated (Box 6)
    - Undated, Major General Lucius Theus, Michigan Aviation Hall of Fame Enshrinement (Box 6)
  - Tuskegee Airmen Detroit Chapter
    - 1985 (Box 6)
    - 1997 (Box 6)
    - 2001 (Box 6)
  - Tuskegee Airmen National Historical Museum
    - 2005 (Box 6)